flarehr.com 2017-06-10

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
Who are we?
‘We’, ‘us’ and ‘our’ or SMSF refer to MyPlanner Australia AFSL 345905 (ACN 140 520 225) as a licensee
authorised to carry on a financial services business and our related body corporates.
Our commitment to protect your privacy
We understand how important it is to protect your personal information. This document sets out our privacy
policy commitment in respect of personal information we hold about you and what we do with that
information.
We recognise that any personal information we collect about you will only be used for the purposes we have
collected it for or as allowed under the law. It is important to us that you are confident that any personal
information we hold about you will be treated in a way which ensures protection of your personal information.
Our commitment in respect of personal information is to abide by the Australian Privacy Principles for the
protection of personal information, as set out in the Privacy Act (1988) and the Privacy Amendment (Enhancing
Privacy Protection) Act 2012 (collectively referred to as the Privacy Act)
and any other relevant law.
Personal information
When we refer to personal information we mean information from which your identity is reasonably apparent.
This information may include information or an opinion about you. The personal information we hold about
you may also include credit information.
AML information is information which is used to assess whether your investment in any way breaches the
terms and conditions of Anti- Money Laundering and Counter Terrorism Financing Act (2006) currently
prevailing in Australia.
The kinds of personal information we may collect about you include your name, date of birth, address, account
details, occupation, tax file number (TFN) and any other information we made need to identify you.
Why we collect your personal information
We collect personal information for the purposes of assessing your application to become a member in our
Fund and manage and administer those financial products. We may also collect your personal information for
the purposes of direct marketing and managing our relationship with you. From
time to time we may offer you other products and services.
To enable us to maintain a successful business relationship with you, we may disclose your personal
information to other organisations that provide products or services used or marketed by us. The types of
organisations to which we are likely to disclose information about you include other fund managers, bankers,
                                                                                                             1

accountants, credit reporting bodies, product issuers, investment managers and lawyers. We may also disclose
your personal information to any other organisation that may have or is considering having an interest in your
investment, or in our business.
How do we collect your personal information?
Where reasonable and practical we will collect your personal information directly from you.
We also collect your personal information from people such as accountants and lawyers.
Do we disclose your personal information?
Depending on the product or service you have requested, we may disclose your personal information to:
      your financial planner or authorised representative in relation to your finance investments;
      other organisations that are involved in managing or administering your finance such as third party
          suppliers, printing and postal services, call centres;
      associated businesses that may want to market products to you;
      companies that provide information and infrastructure systems to us;
      anybody who represents you, such as your financial planner, lawyers, and accountants;
      anyone, where you have provided us consent;
      where we are required to do so by law, such as under the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter Terrorism
          Financing Act 2006 (Cth); or
      an organisation providing verification of your identity, including on-line verification of your identity
      data aggregators who collate and report information between us and our business partners and /or
          you.
      our authorised representatives when it is commercially prudent to do so;
      financial institutions including stockbrokers, custodians, fund managers and portfolio service providers
          and other entity that administer your financial products;
      insurers, if you obtain insurance through us; or
      your employer, referees or identity verification services.
Prior to disclosing any of your personal information to another person or organisation, we will take all
reasonable steps to satisfy ourselves that:
     A. the person or organisation has a commitment to protecting your personal information at least equal to
          our commitment, or
     B. you have consented to us making the disclosure.
We may use cloud storage to store the personal information we hold about you. The cloud storage and the IT
servers may be located inside or outside Australia.
Direct marketing
From time to time we may use your personal information to provide you with current information about
finance, offers you may find of interest, changes to our organisation, or new products or services being offered
by us or any company we are associated with.
If you do not wish to receive marketing information, you may at any time decline to receive such information by
telephoning us on (07) 5560 2300 or by writing to us at either adviserservices@myplanner.com.au or PO Box
902 Southport BC QLD 4215. If the direct marketing is by email you may also use the unsubscribe function. We
will not charge you for giving effect to your request and will take all reasonable steps to meet your request at
the earliest possible opportunity.
                                                                                                                 2

Updating your personal information
It is important to us that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. During the
course of our relationship with you we may ask you to inform us if any of your personal information has
changed.
If you wish to make any changes to your personal information, you may contact us. We will generally rely on
you to ensure the information we hold about you is accurate or complete.
Access and correction to your personal information
We will provide you with access to the personal information we hold about you. You may request access to any
of the personal information we hold about you at any time. We may charge a fee for our costs of retrieving and
supplying the information to you.
Depending on the type of request that you make we may respond to your request immediately, otherwise we
usually respond to you within seven days of receiving your request. We may need to contact other entities to
properly investigate your request.
There may be situations where we are not required to provide you with access to your personal information,
for example, if the information relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings, or if your request is
vexatious.
An explanation will be provided to you, if we deny you access to the personal information we hold about you.
If any of the personal information we hold about you is incorrect, inaccurate or out of date you may request
that we correct the information. If appropriate we will correct the personal information at the time of the
request, otherwise, we will provide an initial response to you within seven days of
receiving your request. Where reasonable, and after our investigation, we will provide you with details about
whether we have corrected the personal or credit information within 30 days.
If we refuse to correct personal information we will provide you with our reasons for not correcting the
information.
Using government identifiers
If we collect government identifiers, such as your tax file number, we do not use or disclose this information
other than required by law. We will never use a government identifier in order to identify you.
Business without identifying you
In most circumstances it will be necessary for us to identify you in order to successfully do business with you,
however, where it is lawful and practicable to do so, we will offer you the opportunity of doing business with us
without providing us with personal information, for example, if you make general inquiries about current
promotional offers.
Sensitive information
We will only collect sensitive information about you with your consent. Sensitive information is personal
information that includes information relating to your racial or ethnic origin, political persuasion, memberships
in trade or professional association or trade unions, sexual preferences, criminal record, or health.
                                                                                                                 3

How safe and secure is your personal information that we
hold?
We will take reasonable steps to protect your personal information by storing it in a secure environment. We
may store your personal information in paper and electronic form. We will also take reasonable steps to
protect any personal information from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.
Complaints
If you are dissatisfied with how we have dealt with your personal information, or you have a complaint about
our compliance with the Privacy Act and the Credit Reporting Code, you may contact our complaints officer on
(07) 5560 2300 or by writing to us at either:
                    Email: compliance@myplanner.com.au or
                    Complaints Handling Manager
                    Level 3, 26 Marine Parade, Southport, Queensland 4215
We will acknowledge your complaint within seven days. We will provide you with a decision on your compliant
within 30 days.
If you are dissatisfied with the response of our complaints officer you may make a compliant to our External
Dispute Resolution Scheme, Financial Ombudsman Service Limited which can be contacted on either:
                    Ph: 1300 78 08 08 or
                    GPO Box 3 Melbourne Victoria 3001 or
Privacy Commissioner who can be contacted on either www.oaic.gov.au or 1300 363 992.
Further information
You may request further information about the way we manage your personal information by contacting us.
                                                                                                             4

Australian privacy principles
The Privacy Act includes 13 privacy principles that regulate the handling of personal information. We have
adopted these privacy principles in full. A summary table of the privacy principle and what we do to manage
your information is outlined in the following table.
APP 1 — Open and transparent management               SMSF manage personal information in an open
of personal information                               and transparent way. This includes having a clearly expressed and
                                                      up to date APP privacy policy.
APP 2 — Anonymity and pseudonymity                    SMSF will give individuals the option of not
                                                      identifying themselves, or of using a pseudonym. Limited
                                                      exceptions apply
APP 3 — Collection of solicited personal              Outlines when SMSF can collect personal
information                                           information that is solicited. It applies higher standards to the
                                                      collection of ‘sensitive’ information.
APP 4 — Dealing with unsolicited personal             We have adopted a policy to ensure how SMSF
information                                           must deal with unsolicited personal information
APP 5 — Notification of the collection of             Outlines when and in what circumstances SMSF
personal information                                  collects personal information and when we must notify an
                                                      individual of certain matters.
APP 6 — Use or disclosure of personal                 Outlines the circumstances in which SMSF may
information                                           use or disclose personal information that it holds.
APP 7 — Direct marketing                              We will only use or disclose personal
                                                      information for direct marketing purposes if certain conditions are
                                                      met.
APP 8 — Cross-border disclosure of personal           SMSF will take care to protect personal
information                                           information before it is disclosed overseas
                                                                                                                   5

APP 9 — Adoption, use or disclosure of                SMSF will in limited circumstances adopt a
government related identifiers                        government related identifier of an individual as its own identifier,
                                                      or use or disclose a government related identifier of an individual.
APP 10 — Quality of personal information              SMSF will take reasonable steps to ensure the
                                                      personal information it collects is accurate, up to date and
                                                      complete. We will also take reasonable steps to ensure the
                                                      personal information we use or discloses is accurate, up to date,
                                                      complete and relevant, having regard to the purpose of the use or
                                                      disclosure.
APP 11 — Security of personal information             SMSF must take reasonable steps to protect
                                                      personal information it holds from misuse, interference and loss,
                                                      and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. SMSF
                                                      has obligations to destroy or de-identify personal information in
                                                      certain circumstances.
APP 12 — Access to personal information               SMSF understands its obligations when an
                                                      individual requests to be given access to personal information held
                                                      about them by us.
                                                      This includes a requirement to provide access
                                                      unless a specific exception applies.
APP 13 — Correction of personal information           SMSF understands its obligations in relation to
                                                      correcting the personal information it holds about individuals
Change in our privacy policy
We are constantly reviewing all of our policies and attempt to keep up to date with market expectations.
Technology is constantly changing, as is the law and market place practices.
As a consequence we may change this privacy policy from time to time or as the need arises. You may request
this privacy policy in an alternative form.
This Privacy Policy came into existence on 12 March 2014
MYPLANNER AUSTRALIA PTY LTD, ABN 28 140 520 225, Australian Financial Services Licence Number 345905
Level 3, 26 Marine Parade, Southport, Qld 4215 Phone 07 5560 2300 Email: compliance@myplannerls.com.au
                                                                                                                 6
